[Speaker 1] Good afternoon, Your Honor. We
[Speaker 1] 're here in the matter of Elmira
[Speaker 1] Jasmine Davis. Case number 25JU
[Speaker 1] 04261.
[Speaker 1] Today's date is March 11, 2026.
[Speaker 1] This is the time and date set
[Speaker 1] for a motion hearing in this
[Speaker 1] matter.
[Speaker 1] Yasmin Wadia on behalf of the
[Speaker 1] Attorney General's Office, on
[Speaker 1] behalf of the Oregon Department
[Speaker 1] of Human Services,
[Speaker 1] emergency caseworker David Mil
[Speaker 1] ne on behalf of the child in
[Speaker 1] this matter,
[Speaker 1] counsel Ryan Lotzke. Mother
[Speaker 1] Ashley Penn is not present and
[Speaker 1] appears first is proceeding
[Speaker 1] pro site. Father Alquan Davis
[Speaker 1] is represented by counsel Yv
[Speaker 1] onne Moles. On behalf of the
[Speaker 1] CASA program this afternoon,
[Speaker 1] CASA supervisor. Okay, so we
[Speaker 2] got a call from Ms. Penn today
[Speaker 2] and one of her issues was that
[Speaker 2] she did not receive the mailed
[Speaker 2] notice because we mailed
the notice per the rules for
[Speaker 1] these types of hearings. And
[Speaker 1] she did call in because I
[Speaker 1] believe
[Speaker 2] Mr. Milne, you mentioned it to
[Speaker 2] her. So she said we had transp
[Speaker 2] osed two numbers. Now, I
[Speaker 2] will note that mom also has a
[Speaker 2] pending landlord-tenant matter
[Speaker 2] with the numbers as she says
[Speaker 2] the address
[Speaker 2] numbers are. But it does appear
[Speaker 2] her previous Multnomah County
[Speaker 2] cases had the address as
[Speaker 2] we had it. Just two numbers
[Speaker 2] different in the middle of the
[Speaker 2] address. So, but that was the
[Speaker 2] address we had from day one. So
[Speaker 2] at this point in time, because
[Speaker 2] of the nature of the hearing,
[Speaker 2] she did want to appear by phone
[Speaker 2] . She has called and made some
[Speaker 2] emails. But motions to dismiss
[Speaker 2] are evidentiary hearings that
[Speaker 2] require in-person appearances.
[Speaker 2] So at this point in time, we're
[Speaker 2] gonna pick a new date and we
[Speaker 2] will send the notice to the
[Speaker 2] modified address so we
[Speaker 2] can do March 18 at 9 a.m. miss
[Speaker 2] moles miss Murphy mr. Rotsky
[Speaker 2] all right so I'll do a
[Speaker 2] short order continuing it over
[Speaker 2] and we will issue a notice out
[Speaker 2] this afternoon
[Speaker 2] and again it requires in-person
[Speaker 2] appearance. All right anything
[Speaker 2] else we need to address? Okay
[Speaker 2] so
[Speaker 2] Ms. Mulzell, I'll let you catch
[Speaker 2] your client up. All right and I
[Speaker 2] 'll put a little check mark that
[Speaker 2] he showed up.
[Speaker 2] Fines or not fines, it's what
[Speaker 2] the court finds. So with a good
[Speaker 4] morning, your honor, we're here
[Speaker 4] in the matter of Almeera Davis
[Speaker 4] case 25 G is 04261. On behalf
[Speaker 4] of the attorney general's
[Speaker 4] office, Hannah Vaughn, you're
[Speaker 4] representing my client, the
[Speaker 4] Oregon Department of Human
[Speaker 4] Services, Child Welfare. Mr.
[Speaker 4] Milne is present on behalf of D
[Speaker 4] HS. Mr. Lotzky on behalf of the
[Speaker 4] child.
[Speaker 4] Mother is not present and not
[Speaker 4] represented. Father is present
[Speaker 4] in the courtroom with Ms. Moles
[Speaker 4] . We also don't have the COSA
[Speaker 4] today. This is the time and
[Speaker 4] place set, Your Honor, for mom
[Speaker 4] 's motion that is unspecific and
[Speaker 4] unclear about really what is
[Speaker 4] being requested.
[Speaker 2] Are you prepared to address it?
[Speaker 4] I'm happy to, Judge, if you'd
[Speaker 4] like me to.
[Speaker 4] So let's kind of break it down.
[Speaker 2] Special appearance and
[Speaker 2] objection to proceed. I think I
[Speaker 2] read that as mom saying that
[Speaker 2] the court does not have
[Speaker 2] jurisdiction over her. Do you
[Speaker 2] wish to address that?
[Speaker 4] Your Honor, I'm very unclear on
[Speaker 4] the basis for which she
[Speaker 4] believes that we don't have a
[Speaker 4] jurisdiction.
[Speaker 4] She's hyper-focused, it appears
[Speaker 4] , through her pleading on the O
[Speaker 4] ARs and on a procedural process
[Speaker 4] that's outside of the scope of
[Speaker 4] this court.
[Speaker 4] So that's an administrative
[Speaker 4] process where there is
[Speaker 4] administrative relief if there
[Speaker 4] isn't compliance as it relates
[Speaker 4] to CPS assessments.
[Speaker 4] That's not related to the
[Speaker 4] juvenile court's jurisdiction.
[Speaker 4] The juvenile court's
[Speaker 4] jurisdiction is based on the
[Speaker 4] pleadings that were filed in
[Speaker 4] this specific case.
[Speaker 4] and the process that was filed
[Speaker 4] as well as this court
[Speaker 4] establishing dependency
[Speaker 4] jurisdiction under the juvenile
[Speaker 4] code.
[Speaker 4] I have no information to
[Speaker 4] believe that, and there's
[Speaker 4] nothing in the motion that
[Speaker 4] would suggest that anything
[Speaker 4] would disrupt that jurisd
[Speaker 4] ictional authority.
[Speaker 4] And so I'm, and she's not here
[Speaker 4] to give me more information.
[Speaker 4] And so I feel like we're at a
[Speaker 4] point, Judge, where nothing in
[Speaker 4] the pleading would suggest that
[Speaker 4] I would need to put on the
[Speaker 4] evidence.
[Speaker 4] court record itself is dispos
[Speaker 4] itive of the fact that this
[Speaker 4] court has jurisdiction. So is
[Speaker 4] there anything more that you
[Speaker 4] would hope to hear from her?
[Speaker 2] Not on that. Okay. Mr. Lotzke,
[Speaker 2] do you wish to be heard on what
[Speaker 2] , and again, correct me if I'm
[Speaker 2] wrong, attorneys, if you think
[Speaker 2] that that's, I think, her first
[Speaker 2] motion is a jurisdictional one.
[Speaker 3] That is the way I read it, Your
[Speaker 3] Honor. Ms. Bowles, is that the
[Speaker 2] way you read it as well? Yeah,
[Speaker 1] it was my understanding that
[Speaker 1] she was focused on the
[Speaker 1] assessment and notice on the
[Speaker 1] And without the process being
[Speaker 1] followed on the family
[Speaker 1] assessment, therefore there can
[Speaker 1] 't be any juvenile court
[Speaker 1] involvement.
[Speaker 1] But as we all know, those two
[Speaker 1] processes are entirely separate
[Speaker 1] from each other.
[Speaker 1] And we don't have facts about
[Speaker 1] the process on the assessment
[Speaker 1] side, but it's also not
[Speaker 1] relevant in this jurisdictional
[Speaker 2] case.
[Speaker 2] Mr. Lotzky, anything you wish
[Speaker 3] to add?
[Speaker 3] I think Mother Shona has
[Speaker 3] received actual notice of these
[Speaker 3] proceedings.
[Speaker 3] I think she's availed herself
[Speaker 3] or attempted to avail herself
[Speaker 3] of the court by filing these
[Speaker 3] motions and is yet to appear.
[Speaker 3] Okay, so what I would first
[Speaker 2] note as what I perceive is a
[Speaker 2] motion on the jurisdictional
[Speaker 2] issue, I would state that
[Speaker 2] number one venue is clearly
[Speaker 2] proper in this court.
[Speaker 2] We have the physical presence
[Speaker 2] of mother within this county, a
[Speaker 2] father within this county,
[Speaker 2] child within this county in the
[Speaker 2] alleged incident.
[Speaker 2] happen in this county. Further,
[Speaker 2] under the UCCJEA, Oregon is the
[Speaker 2] proper state, so I have venue,
[Speaker 2] I have jurisdiction over all
[Speaker 2] parties, and it is clear that
[Speaker 2] Ms. Penn is hyper-focused on a
[Speaker 2] lot of
[Speaker 2] the parts that would come under
[Speaker 2] civil cases, but this is a
[Speaker 2] juvenile case, and service can
[Speaker 2] be
[Speaker 2] effectuated in ways that you
[Speaker 2] can't in a regular civil case,
[Speaker 2] and vice versa, with specific
[Speaker 2] rules.
[Speaker 2] And when it comes to that,
[Speaker 2] there is other types of service
[Speaker 2] , and the court did proceed
[Speaker 2] under the
[Speaker 2] Alternative Diligent Efforts
[Speaker 2] statute contained within the Ju
[Speaker 2] venile Code. Also, as to
[Speaker 2] jurisdiction,
[Speaker 2] the court did hear a prima fac
[Speaker 2] ie case and found that the court
[Speaker 2] had enough evidence on a prima
[Speaker 2] facie
[Speaker 2] case to which to find
[Speaker 2] jurisdiction. So mother's
[Speaker 2] motion to find that there's no
[Speaker 2] jurisdiction is
[Speaker 2] denied. Second, to respond to
[Speaker 2] receive notice of founded
[Speaker 2] allegations or specific alleg
[Speaker 2] ation of harm,
[Speaker 2] I am not quite sure what that
[Speaker 2] is. And when she talks about
[Speaker 2] under certain statutes that
[Speaker 2] jurisdiction only attaches
[Speaker 2] under certain things and that D
[Speaker 2] HS makes a founded determination
,
[Speaker 2] as this parties in this court
[Speaker 2] well know, as I always say, I
[Speaker 2] don't care what DHS finds or
[Speaker 2] not
[Speaker 2] finds, it's what the court
[Speaker 2] finds. So whether they had a
[Speaker 2] founded or unfounded is not
[Speaker 2] dispositive of
[Speaker 2] anything, the court made the
[Speaker 2] finding of the jurisdictional
[Speaker 2] basis. And again, when she's
[Speaker 2] talking about the parent with
[Speaker 2] written notice of the nature,
[Speaker 2] we proceeded under 419B 914,
[Speaker 2] because that statute is
[Speaker 2] specifically designed for
[Speaker 2] parents who cannot be found, or
[Speaker 2] shall we say,
[Speaker 2] choose not to be found. And in
[Speaker 2] this case, we all know Ms. Penn
[Speaker 2] is well aware of the
[Speaker 2] allegations.
[Speaker 2] We all know that she's filing
[Speaker 2] motions. We are aware that,
[Speaker 2] well, considering how many
[Speaker 2] times she
[Speaker 2] has called court staff, she
[Speaker 2] certainly knows of the
[Speaker 2] proceedings. She has actual
[Speaker 2] notice
[Speaker 2] of these hearings and has
[Speaker 2] called in about them. So she is
[Speaker 2] well aware of what is going on,
[Speaker 2] and has chosen to not
[Speaker 2] participate.
[Speaker 2] Now, when we look at, again, so
[Speaker 2] service can be formed in other
[Speaker 2] ways.
[Speaker 2] Service also is admissible in
[Speaker 2] juvenile court by posting.
[Speaker 2] That is another thing where
[Speaker 2] someone does not get an actual
[Speaker 2] piece of paper.
[Speaker 2] It's actually posted on a board
[Speaker 2] at the courthouse or in a
[Speaker 2] newspaper.
[Speaker 2] That's not receiving a physical
[Speaker 2] piece of paper, but that, again
[Speaker 2] , is another method of service
[Speaker 2] that is allowed under the
[Speaker 2] statute in juvenile court.
[Speaker 2] So it is not dispositive in any
[Speaker 2] way, shape, or form that ODHS
[Speaker 2] has not handed mom a piece of
[Speaker 2] paper.
[Speaker 4] Judge Rini? Judge Rini?
[Speaker 2] Some of this I am not sure what
[Speaker 2] she is asking for.
[Speaker 2] Right. She also asked for DHS
[Speaker 2] records. That is, has she subpo
[Speaker 2] enaed ODHS records?
[Speaker 4] I'm not aware, Your Honor, of a
[Speaker 4] subpoena, and I have, I mean,
[Speaker 4] she's entitled to regular
[Speaker 4] discovery in this case as a
[Speaker 4] party, and we've been complying
[Speaker 4] with that requirement.
[Speaker 2] And I believe she said you did
[Speaker 2] forward that?
[Speaker 2] Yep.
[Speaker 2] Okay.
[Speaker 4] So I don't know. I mean, if
[Speaker 4] there are further records that
[Speaker 4] aren't included in 419B-881
[Speaker 4] that she's requesting, there
[Speaker 4] are processes where she can
[Speaker 4] come and submit that through an
[Speaker 4] administrative process through
[Speaker 4] DHS to request an entire case
[Speaker 4] file.
[Speaker 4] I'm not aware that she has done
[Speaker 4] that, nor have I received a sub
[Speaker 4] poena. And at this point, I don
[Speaker 4] 't even know what it is that she
[Speaker 4] 's specifically asking or feels
[Speaker 4] like she doesn't have.
[Speaker 4] I mean, there's a list of
[Speaker 4] things that are outside of the
[Speaker 4] scope, it looks like, of 881,
[Speaker 4] and we would be happy to
[Speaker 4] respond to that subpoena if she
[Speaker 4] were to send it to us for
[Speaker 4] additional records.
[Speaker 2] Okay, so I think when we go to
[Speaker 2] the relief requested, I think I
[Speaker 2] responded to one that mother
[Speaker 2] was served effectively under 4
[Speaker 2] 19 B.914.
[Speaker 2] So that part won't be continued
[Speaker 2] .
[Speaker 2] She asked for DHS to produce on
[Speaker 2] the record before any further
[Speaker 2] proceedings the founded alleg
[Speaker 2] ation.
[Speaker 2] Again, that is irrelevant to
[Speaker 2] the court process.
[Speaker 2] That is a separate track,
[Speaker 2] internal.
[Speaker 2] We can have founded allegations
[Speaker 2] with no jurisdiction.
[Speaker 2] And we can have jurisdiction
[Speaker 2] without a finding in an
[Speaker 2] administrative file.
[Speaker 2] It's all what happens in court.
[Speaker 2] So number three, she said,
[Speaker 2] if DHS cannot produce a founded
[Speaker 2] determination and proof of
[Speaker 2] notice,
[Speaker 2] dismiss or stay the proceedings
[Speaker 2] .
[Speaker 2] However, again, because a
[Speaker 2] founded determination does not
[Speaker 2] have
[Speaker 2] a practical effect or is not
[Speaker 2] required for jurisdiction, the
[Speaker 2] motion to dismiss is denied for
[Speaker 2] lack
[Speaker 2] of jurisdiction. For number
[Speaker 2] four, she wants the court to
[Speaker 2] take judicial notice that DHS
[Speaker 2] don't produce records
[Speaker 2] containing no documented
[Speaker 2] finding of risk. Now again, the
[Speaker 2] records the
[Speaker 2] court receives are different
[Speaker 2] than what is contained in the D
[Speaker 2] HS file and may be different
[Speaker 2] than the discovery received by
[Speaker 2] the party.
[Speaker 2] The court only gets certain
[Speaker 2] documents.
[Speaker 2] And so I can't take judicial
[Speaker 2] notice of that fact.
[Speaker 2] That's not a readily ascertain
[Speaker 2] able concrete fact,
[Speaker 2] like did St. Patrick's Day fall
[Speaker 2] on a Tuesday this year?
[Speaker 2] That's judicial notice.
[Speaker 2] Or I can take judicial notice
[Speaker 2] of the date something was filed
[Speaker 2] ,
[Speaker 2] but not that nothing was there.
[Speaker 2] That is against the rules for
[Speaker 2] what judicial notice means.
[Speaker 2] I cannot and will not order the
[Speaker 2] clerk to docket this filing
[Speaker 2] and all future filings without
[Speaker 2] alteration or rejection.
[Speaker 2] If they are not properly filed,
[Speaker 2] they will be rejected.
[Speaker 2] But otherwise, if mom properly
[Speaker 2] files something, they will be
[Speaker 2] received.
[Speaker 2] And I will note for the record,
[Speaker 2] mother has tried to file by
[Speaker 2] email.
[Speaker 2] Nobody is allowed to file by
[Speaker 2] I mean, otherwise, I mean, what
[Speaker 2] , if she emails a clerk in the
[Speaker 2] probate department, they're
[Speaker 2] going to file?
[Speaker 2] No, it's got to be filed
[Speaker 2] properly.
[Speaker 2] Attorneys must do it by file
[Speaker 2] and serve.
[Speaker 2] Pro se people can do it by
[Speaker 2] physically bringing in the
[Speaker 2] documents to file.
[Speaker 2] She wants to produce the court
[Speaker 2] files required by the statutory
[Speaker 2] scheme.
[Speaker 2] I will note that the court has
[Speaker 2] offered for her to come and
[Speaker 2] review the file in person.
[Speaker 2] Due to the nature of the
[Speaker 2] records, we are not going to
[Speaker 2] release a copy to her,
[Speaker 2] but she can come in and see
[Speaker 2] everything.
[Speaker 2] And that was offered to her,
[Speaker 2] and she declined.
[Speaker 2] I don't know what other such
[Speaker 2] relief she deems necessary
[Speaker 2] to protect mother's fundamental
[Speaker 2] constitutional right.
[Speaker 2] Mother has the right to appear,
[Speaker 2] to participate,
[Speaker 2] to apply for court-appointed
[Speaker 2] attorney.
[Speaker 2] She has done none of those.
[Speaker 2] As it comes to her personal
[Speaker 2] jurisdiction, the subject
[Speaker 2] matter jurisdiction,
[Speaker 2] Those are all proper within
[Speaker 2] this court, so she may deny
[Speaker 2] that she's appearing, but we're
[Speaker 2] already past that point.
[Speaker 2] So she then asked for her
[Speaker 2] mother to request the court
[Speaker 2] order DHS to produce within 48
[Speaker 2] hours complete copies of all
[Speaker 2] documents in the DHS file.
[Speaker 2] Again, that is not in my pur
[Speaker 2] view outside of discovery.
[Speaker 2] She has a means of accessing
[Speaker 2] the entire court file, and she
[Speaker 2] has not yet done so.
[Speaker 2] So all those things that she
[Speaker 2] asked from there, she can get
[Speaker 2] those by going through the
[Speaker 2] proper channels,
[Speaker 2] through DHS, through the
[Speaker 2] administrative process, and
[Speaker 2] then all court orders, she
[Speaker 2] again can come and review the
[Speaker 2] file.
[Speaker 2] So, Ms. Moles, anything you
[Speaker 2] wish to address on those?
[Speaker 2] Okay, Mr. Rotsky, anything you
[Speaker 2] wish to address?
[Speaker 3] No, thank you, Your Honor.
[Speaker 2] Okay, Ms. Moles, anything?
[Speaker 2] Ms. Moles, I'm sorry.
[Speaker 2] Ms. Vaughn.
[Speaker 4] No, Your Honor, thank you very
[Speaker 4] much.
[Speaker 2] Okay, so I'll do a short order.
[Speaker 2] Thank you, everyone.
[Speaker 2] That'll be the order.
[Speaker 4] Thank you, Judge.
Thank you.
Perfect.